这是二零二三年普通高等学校招生
全国统一考试英语科听力部分第二次考试。
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意。
回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish. Tuesday, Italian.
Wednesday, German.
And Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
OK. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form and
some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
十，请看听力部分第一节。
第一节，听下面五段对话。
每段对话后有一个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关。
分小题和阅读下一小题，
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容。
Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
Yes, it's nine fifteen.
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择
项，并将其标在试卷上。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间
阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Tom, shall we buy a gift for Maggie's birthday?
Yes, but I don't know what she likes.
Let's call her roommate Sophia.
She might know what to buy for her.
Could you check this bill for me?
I don't think it's right.
Certainly. First, did you have two coffees?
Oh, did I?
Yes, you had one before the meal, and another after.
I I Hi, Mike.
What are you doing here?
I remember you've finished your final exams.
Yes, but I've got to select next term's courses.
Oh, that's good.
We can do this together.
Yes, term's good.
this How much time do we have before the movie?
We won't have to hurry, will we?
Don't worry. It's 6.30 now.
We still have two hours.
It takes only 30 minutes to get there.
Good morning, sir.
I'd like to ask you a few questions, if I may.
Well, I'm waiting for my flight, so I guess I can, if you make it brief.
第一节到此结束。
第二节。
听下面五段对话或独白。
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或。
独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
Hello, can I speak to the sales manager, please?
I'm the sales manager.
Can I help you?
Right. Well, I phoned two days ago to say I hadn't received my order, and I'm
ringing again to say it still hasn't arrived.
Can I just take your name, please?
Yes, it's Frank Edward.
Ah, Mr. Edward.
I think there's been a problem with that order.
What kind of problem?
You see, part of the order didn't arrive here at the storehouse, so we couldn't send
it out until we'd received everything from the supplier.
Well, surely that was not my problem.
I placed this order weeks ago.
Yeah, I'm sorry about this, Mr.
Edward, but we'll do everything we can to send this out to you today.
Right. Please do.
I am badly in need of it.
Hello, can I speak to the sales manager, please?
Yes, I'm the sales manager.
Can I help you?
Right. Well, I phoned two days ago to say I hadn't received my order, and I'm
ringing again to say it still hasn't arrived.
Can I just take your name, please?
Yes, it's Frank Edward.
Ah, Mr. Edward.
I think there's been a problem with that order.
What kind of problem?
You see, part of the order didn't arrive here at the storehouse, so we couldn't send
it out until we'd received everything from the supplier.
Well, surely that was not my problem.
I placed this order weeks ago.
Yeah, I'm sorry about this, Mr.
Edward, but we'll do everything we can to send this out to you today.
Right. Please do.
I am badly in need of it.
听下面一段对话，回答第八。
至第十三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Hmm, there's a wonderful smell of fresh coffee in the air.
Oh, welcome! This is the Festo Coffee.
It's the best in the world, and you can only get it here.
And where is here?
The Festo Island.
Festo Island? So that's where we are.
Goodness, we really have gone off course.
Where are you heading?
We set off at Cape Island and were supposed to be sailing toward Dennis Island, but
we got lost when our GPS broke.
you don't have to worry about that.
My brother fixes things.
I'm sure he can help.
Let me take it for you, and if you can come back at four o it will be ready,
hopefully. Brilliant. And while I'm here, can I buy some of those coffee beans?
Hmm, there's a wonderful smell of fresh coffee in the air.
Oh, welcome! This is the Festo Coffee.
It's the best in the world, and you can only get it here.
And where is here?
The Festo Island.
The Festo Island?
So that's where we are.
Goodness, we really have gone off course.
Where are you heading?
We set off at Cape Island and were supposed to be sailing toward Dennis Island, but
we got lost when our GPS broke.
Oh, you don't have to worry about that.
My brother fixes things.
I'm sure he can help.
Let me take it for you, and if you can come back at four o it will be ready,
hopefully. Brilliant. And while I'm here, can I buy some of those coffee beans?
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至第十三
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Hey, Alexis. Great to see you.
Ready for a bit of skating?
Yeah, but I haven't been skating for ages, Martha.
Me neither, but I'm a natural when it comes to sports.
So, what's in your bag?
A few things.
A hat, gloves, a jacket, the usual skating safety equipment.
We're only going around the Well, you never know.
I don't bother with hats and gloves or that sort of things.
I find it gets in the way.
Don't you worry about getting hurt?
No, I love adventures.
Just the other day, I went climbing on this climbing wall, and I didn't even use
safety equipment. If I get hurt, I just ignore the pain.
Well, I'm not that brave.
Hey, come on.
Let's get going.
Wait a second.
I need to get my equipment on.
Hey, Alexis. Great to see you.
Ready for a bit of skating?
Yeah, but I haven't been skating for ages, Martha.
Me neither, but I'm a natural when it comes to sports.
So, what's in your bag?
A few things.
A hat, gloves, a jacket, the usual skating safety equipment.
We're only going around the Well, you never know.
I don't bother with hats and gloves or that sort of things.
I find it gets in the way.
Don't you worry about getting hurt?
No, I love adventures.
Just the other day, I went climbing on this climbing wall, and I didn't even use
safety equipment. If I get hurt, I just ignore the pain.
Well, I'm not that brave.
Hey, come on.
Let's get going.
Wait a I need to get my equipment on.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至第十七
四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间
阅读这四个小题。
Wait a I need equipment I my on.
on. Wait a second.
I equipment on.
Hello, Claudia. Do you remember me?
Of course. Hello, Chris.
You look well.
It must be eight years since you left school.
That's right. You were four years below me.
I was in the same year as your older sister, Stephanie.
Yes. You two were very close.
Is Stephanie here for the 50 -year celebration of our school?
No. She is in Denmark for business.
What are you doing now?
After school. I got a at university, and I am majoring in business studies.
That sounds interesting.
I got a job as an interpreter.
What languages do you speak?
Apart from English, I speak French and German.
I didn't get on well with my French teacher here at school, so I dropped the subject
at the end of my fifth year.
Where do you study?
In London. I enjoy living in London.
I sometimes travel to different parts of Britain with my boss to do interpreting for
him. Next week, he has a conference in London.
Will you have time to call and visit me while you are in the area?
Yes, I'd love to.
I'll give you my phone number.
Ring me in the evening.
Thank you. We'll be able to have more time to catch up.
Hello, Claudia. Do you remember me?
Of course. Hello, Chris.
You look well.
It must be eight years since you left school.
That's right. You were four years below me.
I was in the same year as your older sister, Stephanie.
Yes. You two were very close.
Is Stephanie here for the 50 -year celebration of our school?
No, she is in Denmark for business.
What are you doing now?
After school. I got a place at university and I am majoring in business studies.
That sounds interesting.
I got a job as an interpreter.
What languages do you speak?
Apart from English, I speak French and German.
I didn't get on well with my French teacher here at school, so I dropped the subject
at the end of my fifth year.
Where do you study?
In London. I enjoy living in London.
I sometimes travel to different parts of Britain with my boss to do interpreting for
him. Next week he has a conference in London.
Will you have time to call and visit me while you are in the area?
Yes, I'd love to.
I'll give you my phone number.
Ring me in the evening.
Thank you. We'll be able to have more time to catch up.
听下面一段独白，回答第十八至第二十
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Welcome aboard our City Tour Bus.
First, let me tell you about the tour.
We're going to travel through the most historic parts of the city for about an hour,
with lots of chances for you to take photos or just enjoy the wonderful buildings
like the City Hall and the Royal Theatre.
Then we'll drop you off at the museum.
You have about two hours there.
At 11.30 we'll start for our next destination,
the Stanley Market.
You may buy some fruit and cheese from the marketplace and have a light meal in the
park nearby. But please, please,
come back on time at 1.30 p.m.
We can't wait for any latecomers.
Now I'll give you some instructions on safety.
Welcome aboard our City Tour Bus.
First, let me tell you about the tour.
We're going to travel through the most historic parts of the city for about an hour,
with lots of chances for you to take photos or just enjoy the wonderful buildings
like the City Hall and the Royal Theatre.
Then we'll drop you off at the museum.
You have about two hours there.
At 11.30 we'll start for our next destination,
the Stanley Market.
You may buy some fruit and cheese from the marketplace and have a light meal in the
park nearby. But please, please,
come back on time at 1.30 p.m.
We can't wait for any latecomers.
Now I'll give you some instructions on safety.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有。
两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案
转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
听力部分第二次考试到此结束。